Melanie Hall

www.github.com/mhall313

www.linkedin.com/in/hallmelanie

Richmond, Virginia (804) 346-7909 hallmt313@gmail.com

SUMMARY

High performing analyst with 8 years of finance and accounting experience turned software engineer. With my mathematical background, logic based analyst skills and excellent presentation skills, I will be a strong resource on your team.

EXPERIENCE

Capital One, Richmond, VA — Financial Analyst

JAN 2017 - PRESENT

Financial Planning & Analysis Infrastructure Finance including forecasting, annual budget planning, variance reviews, labor strategy, and allocations.

Active member of Diversity, Inclusion and Belonging committee and stood up Business Resource Group for Women in iFinance.

BH Media Group Inc., Henrico, VA — Financial Analyst

IUL 2015 - IAN 2017

Financial analysis of east coast production teams on income statement, cost drivers and profitability

Improved efficiency in production accounting by automating data entry Excel workbooks for over 100 cost centers.

Manage the east coast production accounting team, including billing, budgeting productions sites and presenting outcomes and forecast to Controllers, Pressroom leadership team.

AgilQuest, Richmond, VA — Accountant

SEP 2014 - JUL 2015

Increased client satisfaction and trust by producing data analysis reports for external presentations.

Increased efficiency and clarity of internal and external project and time tracking with new, improved processes.

Accurately process current and long term deferred revenue schedules and record appropriate journal entries.

Reconciliation of banking and credit lines, create and maintain depreciation and long-term asset schedules.

PORTFOLIO

https://mhall313.github.io/

SKILLS

Development:
HTML
CSS
JavaScript/jQuery
Responsive Design
Bootstrap
Handlebars
Local Storage
API Interaction
Heroku
Git
(Pending)
Session Storage
IndexedDB
React.js

Data Analytics:

G Suite Microsoft 365 Hyperion Smart View OneStream

Finance:

Quickbooks Presentation & Communication

EDUCATION

University of Richmond Coding Bootcamp - Full Stack Flex Program

AUG 2020 - JAN 2021

Virginia TechB.S. Mathematics

2007 - 2011

Northern Virginia Community College A.S. Accounting and Business Management

2013 - 2015